Finding Aid for the Joseph Byrne Lockey Papers LSC.0127
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Central America
  - 20. Nicaragua (Dispatches)--Privateer in William Walker--Filibustering to, 1866
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, June 15, 1856.; 8.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.57). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, June 22, 1856.; 9.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.58). (Box 2)
      - Walker, William. Decree, June 20, 1856.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 58 - June 22, 1856 from Granada, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
      - Walker, William. Address to the People of Nicaragua. Granada, June 20, 1856.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 58 - June 22, 1856 from Granada, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
      - Walker, William. Address to the Army. Granada, June 20, 1856.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 58 - June 22, 1856 from Granada, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, June 30, 1856.; 10.; 2pp. (Copy typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.59). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, August 25, 1856.; 11.; 4pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.67). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States in Nicaragua, Leon, November 12, 1861.; 12.; 2pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7 no.11). (Box 2)
      - Dickinson, A.B. to the Honorable Hermdo. Zepeda, Minister of Foreign Relations. Legation of the U.S., Leon, November 8, 1861.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 11 - November 12, 1861 from Leon, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S., Leon, January 14, 1862.; 13.; 2pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7 no.14). (Box 2)
      - Zepeda, Hermendepedo to [A.B. Dickinson]. National Palace, Managua, November 30, 1861.; 1.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure B-14 - January 14, 1862 from Leon, Nicaragua. (Box 2)
      - Dickinson, A.B. to His Excellency, Hermdo. Zepeda. Legation of the United States, Leon, December 26, 1861.; 2.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure C-14 - January 14, 1862 from Leon, Nic'a). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S. in Nicaragua, Leon, February 13, 1862.; 14.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7 no.15). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to [William H. Seward]. Leon, February 13, 1862.; 15.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Leon, March 10, 1862.; 16.; 2pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7 no.16). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States in Nicaragua, June 12, 1862.; 17.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7 no.23). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to William H. Seward. Leon, July 11, 1862.; 18.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.7). (Box 2)
      - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable James R. Partridge. Leon, June 25, 1862.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to Dispatch of July 11, 1862 from Leon Nicaragua). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to the Secy of State. Legation of the U.S. to Nicaragua, San Juan del Norte, July 13, 1863.; 19.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.8 no.10). (Box 2)
      - Zelledon, P. to [A.B. Dickinson]. Government House, Leon, July 3, 1863.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of translation of enclosure 1 to Dispatch no.10 from Legation of the U.S. at San Juan del Norte, July 31, 1863). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to the Honorable Secretary of State. Legation of the United States, San Juan del Norte, August 1, 1863.; 20.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.8 no.12). (Box 2)
      - Dickinson, A.B. to His Excellency Dr. D. Pedro Zeledon. San Juan del Norte, July 13, 1863.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 12 from San Juan del Norte, 1 August 1863). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S., Leon, September 7, 1866.; 21.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.10, no.120). (Box 2)
      - Selva, Buenav a, to A.B. Dickinson. National Palace, Managua, August 22, 1866.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure no.1-120 from Nicaragua, 7 September 1866). (Box 2)
      - Dickinson, A.B. to Señor Don Beunaventura Selva. Legation of the U.S., Leon, August 25, 1866.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure 2-120 from Nicaragua 7 September 1866). (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S., Leon, November 23, 1866.; 22.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.10, no.121). (Box 2)
      - Dickinson, A.B. to His Exy. R. Cortes. Legation of the U.S., Leon, November 22, 1866.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 121 from Nicaragua 7 September 1866). (Box 2)
    - Note., 23.; 1p. Pen. Yellow paper. (Box 2)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S., Leon, December 20, 1866.; 24.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.10 no.123). (Box 2)
      - Cortez, Rosalio to Honorable A.B. Dickinson. National Palace, Managua, November 30, 1866.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of translation of Enclosure 123 from Nicaragua December 20, 1866). (Box 2)
  - 21. Nicaragua (Note)
    - Marcoleta, J. De to the Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, March 18, 1855.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Phillips, W.B. to Mr.L. Cousin. Copy, Washington, March 5, 1855.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to note from Nicaraguan Legation of March 18, 1855). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, April 25, 1855.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Fabens, Joseph W. to James Gordon Bennett. New York, April 23, 1855.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to note from Nicaraguan Legation, April 25, 1855). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Nicaraguan Legation, New York, May 9, 1855.; 3.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcelota, J. de to W.L. Marcy. New York, May 9, 1855.; 4.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Nicaraguan Legation, New York, May 15, 1855.; 5.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of NIcaragua, Washington, May 24, 1855.; 6.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, June 1, 1855.; 7.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to [Unknown]. Nicaraguan Legation, New York, June 2, 1855.; 8.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Cooper, James to Mr. Hopkins. Philadelphia, May 30, 1855.; 1.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, to note of June 2, 1855 from Nicaraguan Legation, New York). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, June 2, 1855.; 9.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Nicaraguan Legation -Nicaraguan Notes, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy., 10.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, I. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, Washington, April 26, 1856.; 11.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Nicaraguan Notes, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Estrada, Jose Maria. Manifesto of the legitimate President of the Republic of Nicaragua, to the governments and people of Central America., 1.; 9pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to note from Nicaraguan Legation, Washington, April 26, 1856). (Box 2)
    - Heiss, John P. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, August 3, 1856.; 12.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Nicaraguan Legation). (Box 2)
    - Salinas, Sebastian to His Excellency, the Secretary of State of the U.S.A. Government House, Leon, August 12, 1856.; 13.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Nicaraguan Legation, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Oaksmith, Appleton to the Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation de Nicaragua, Washington, August 15, 1856.; 14.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Walker, William to His Excellency Franklin Pierce. Granada, July 16, 1856.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to note from Nicaraguan Legation August 15, 1856). (Box 2)
      - Ferrer, F. to the Secretary of State of the U.S. Granada, July 16, 1856.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure 2 to note from Nicaraguan Legation 15 August 1856). (Box 2)
    - Oaksmith, Appleton to Honorable William L. Marcy. Nicaraguan Legation. Willards, August 21, 1856.; 15.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - The Daily Picayune, August 14, 1856.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to note from Nicaraguan Legation August 21, 1856). (Box 2)
    - Oaksmith, Appleton to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation de Nicaragua, Washington, August 23, 1856.; 16.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Oaksmith, Appleton to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, September 18, 1856.; 17.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Irisari, A.J. de to His Excellency W.L. Marcy, Brooklyn, December 5, 1856.; 18.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Nicaraguan Legation, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Irisarri, Antonio I. de to Honorable Lewis Cass. Washington, October 8, 1857.; 19.; (Copy, typewritten, from Nicaraguan Legation). (Box 2)
    - Molina, Luis to H.E. William H. Seward. Washington, April 30, 1864.; 20.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Notes from Nicaraguan Legation, vol.1). (Box 2)
  - 22. Notes
    - Carcache, Eduardo to the Honorable J.M. Clayton. Washington, Translation of a note from the Charge`d'Affaires of Nicaragua (Copy, typewritten, of Nicaraguan Notes, vol.2)., December 27, 1849.; 1.; 2pp. (Box 2)
      - Translation of the Declaration of the Legislative Assembly of Nicaragua, December 27, 1849; 1.; (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure from Nicaraguan Legation). 2pp. (Box 2)
    - Salinas, Sebastian to H.E. The Minister of Foreign Relations of the Supreme Government of the U.S. Government House, Granada, March 17, 1848.; 2.; (Copy, typewritten, of translation of a note from the Minister of Foreign Relations of the State of Nicaragua). 8pp. (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. 4pp. Legation of Nicaragua, Washington, March 20, 1854.; 3.; (Copy, typewritten, from Central American Legations - Nicaragua, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Mayrga, Mateo to His Excellency Don Jose de Marcoleta. Government House, Managua, February 19, 1854.; 1.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to March 20, 1854 from Legation of Nicaragua). (Box 2)
    - Stephens, John L. to Honorable John Forsyth ( received )., Undated - August 17, 1839 or August 17, 1840; 4.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Central America, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Savage, Henry to Honorable J. Buchanan. Guatemala, December 25, 1847.; 5.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Savage, Henry to Honorable James Buchanan. Guatemala, February 5, 1848.; 6.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable James Buchanan. Guatemala, February 12, 1848.; 7.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Buchanan, James to Elijah Hise. Department of State, Washington, June 3, 1848.; 8.; 9pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Instructions to American States, vol.15). (Box 2)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable James Buchanan. Guatemala, August 30, 1848.; 9.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Bentrago, Pablo to H.E. the Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Supreme Government of the United States of the North. Government House, Leon, November 12, 1847.; 10.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Nicaraguan Notes, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Guerrero, J. to His Excellency James K. Polk. Leon, December 15, 1847.; 11.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Nicaraguan Notes, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Clayton, John M. to E. George Squier. Department of State, Washington, May 1, 1849.; 12.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Instructions to American States, vol.15). (Box 2)
    - Squier, E. George to Honorable John M. Clayton. Legation of the U.S., Leon de Nicaragua, )., August 20, 1849; 13.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.2 no.3). (Box 2)
    - Squier, E. George to Honorable John M. Clayton, Leon de Nicaragua, November 9, 1849.; 14.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.2 no.11). (Box 2)
    - Squier, E. George to Honorable John M. Clayton. Legation of the U.S., Leon de Nicaragua, March 8, 1850.; 15.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Dispatches, vol.2 no.25). (Box 2)
    - Squier, E. George to Honorable John M. Clayton. Legation of the U.S. in Central America. La Union, (San Salvador), March 31, 1850.; 16.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Dispatches). (Box 2)
    - Webster, Daniel to Señor Don Felipe Molina. Department of State, Washington, March 31, 1851.; 17.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legation, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable Daniel Webster. Office of the Legation of the U.S., Guatemala, April 21, 1851.; 18.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.3). (Box 2)
    - Molina, F. to [Unknown]. Washington, D.C., July 17, 1851.; 19.; 12pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Derrick, W.S. to Señor Don Felipe Molina. Washington, August 14, 1851.; 20.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Webster, Daniel to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Washington, November 11, 1851.; 21.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Conrad, C.M. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Washington, October 28, 1852.; 22.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Kerr, John Bozman to the Honorable Secretary of State of the United States. Legation of the U.S.A., Leon de Nicaragua, January 13, 1853.; 23.; 5pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.1 no.14). (Box 2)
    - Bozland, Solon to Honorable William L. Marcy. U.S. Legation, Managua, November 10, 1853.; 24.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.1 no.9). (Box 2)
    - Bozland, Solon to Honorable William L. Marcy. U.S. Legation, Managua, January 11, 1854.; 25.; 2pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.1 no.12). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to John L. Marling. Washington, October 4, 1854.; 26.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Instructions to American States, vol.15 no.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to the Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, November 22, 1854.; 27.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Central American Legations - Nicaragua, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, November 30, 1854.; 28.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, December 11, 1854.; 29.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Notes from Central American Legations - Nicaragua, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, December 27, 1854.; 30.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legations - Nicaragua, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Washington, May 4, 1854.; 31.; 9pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legations - Nicaragua, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Felipe Molina. Department of State, Washington, December 19, 1854.; 32.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, April 27, 1854.; 33.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, January 16, 1855.; 34.; 13pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations - Nicaragua, vol.2). (Box 2)
    - Marcoleta, J. de to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, March 14, 1855.; 35.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.2). (Box 2)
      - Phillips, H.B. to Monsieur L. Cousin. Washington City, February 24, 1855.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to note from Nicaraguan Legation 14 March 1855). (Box 2)
  - 23. Notes (Miscellaneous)
    - Ibarra, M.J. to the Foreign Secretary of the United States of North America. National Palace in Guatemala, October 3, 1830.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Other States, B-J, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Molina, Pedro to the Honorable Edward Livingston. Palace of the Government in Guatemala, November 3, 1831.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Other States, B-J, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, May 15, 1855.; 3.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, June 4, 1855.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, August 22, 1856.; 5.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, September 3, 1855.; 6.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Jose de Marcoleta. Department of State, Washington, October 10, 1855.; 7.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Antonio J. de Irisarri. Department of State, Washington, December 6, 1855.; 8.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Nicaraguan Legation. Department of State, Washington, December 10, 1855.; 9.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Luis Molina. Department of State, Washington, December 20, 1855.; 10.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Señor Don Luis Molina. Department of State, Washington, April 25, 1856.; 11.; 5pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, I.L. to Appleton Oaksmith, Esq., Willards'. Department of State, Washington, August 21 1856.; 12.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Domestic Letters, vol.45). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Appleton Oaksmith. Department of State, Washington, September 13, 1856.; 13.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, W.L. to Appleton Oaksmith. Department of State, Washington, September 23, 1856.; 14.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes to Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Cass, Lewis to Señor Don Antonio J. de Yrisarri. Department of State, Washington, April 20, 1858.; 15.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Cass, Lewis to Señor Don Antonio Jose de Irisarri. Department of State, Washington, April 26, 1858.; 16.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Cass, Lewis to Señor Don A.J. de Yrisarri. Department of State, Washington, September 23, 1858.; 17.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Cass, Lewis to Señor Don Luis Molina. Department of State, Washington, November 26, 1860.; 18.; 13pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Seward, William H. to Señor A.J. de Yrisarri. Department of State, Washington, December 24, 1864.; 19.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, A.T. de to W.L. Marcy. New York, November 30, 1855.; 20.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Molina, Luis to the Honorable W.L. Marcy. Washington, December 20, 1855.; 21.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Molina, Luis to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Washington, April 8, 1856.; 22.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Notes from Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, de A.T. to W.L. Marcy. New York, May 19, 1856.; 23.; 6pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Central American Notes, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Molina, Luis to Honorable W.L. Marcy. Washington, May 22, 1856.; 24.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legations, vol.1). (Box 2)
    - Irisarri, A. F. and Luis Molina to the Secretary of State of the U.S. New York, September 14, 1857.; 25.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Legations of Guatemala, Salvador and Costa Rica). (Box 2)
    - Irisarri, A.J. de to the Honorable Lewis Cass. Washington, November 10, 1857.; 26.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, from Legations of Guatemala & Salvador). (Box 2)
      - Martinez, Tomas and Maximo Xerez. Decree. Managua, August 31, 1857.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure to Note of November 10, 1857 from Legations of Guatemala and Salvador). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, A.J. de to H.E. The Secretary of State of the United State. Brooklyn, January 11, 1858.; 27.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, A.J. de to His Excellency Lewis Cass. Brooklyn, January 27, 1858.; 28.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, A.J. de to the Honorable Lewis Cass. Brooklyn, April 16, 1858.; 29.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, A.J. de to Honorable Lewis Cass. Legation of Nicaragua, Brooklyn, April 22, 1858.; 30.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
    - Yrisarri, A.J. de to Honorable Lewis Cass. Brooklyn, September 21, 1858.; 31.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
    - Jerez, Maximo to Honorable Gen. Lewis Cass. Legation of Nicaragua, New York, November 2, 1858.; 32.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
    - Molina, Luis to His Excellency General Lewis Cass. Legation of Costa Rica, Nicaragua and Honduras, Washington, October 2, 1860.; 33.; 7pp. (Copy, typewritten, of notes from Central American Legation, vol.4). (Box 2)
      - Vargas, Tomas to the Commander in Chief. Truxillo, June 21, 1860.; 1.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of first enclosure to October 2, 1860 from Legation of Costa Rica). (Box 2)
      - Hall, Edward and Tomas Armijo to the Licentiate Don Cresencio Gomez. Second enclosure to from Legation of Costa Rica, Nicaragua, and Honduras., October 2, 1860; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten). (Box 2)
      - Alvarado, Casto to Don Santos Guardiola - Omoa, June 24, 1860.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of third enclosure to October 2, 1860 from Legation of Costa Rica, Nicaragua and Honduras). (Box 2)